# PRABIN B. LAMICHHANE

I am a Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science with five years of working experience in Network Security, Anomaly Detection, Machine Learning, Data Science, and Graph Mining. Currently, I am working on research related to anomaly/fraud detection in dynamic networks using graph-based techniques. In M.S., I developed an algorithm to find the critical stepping stone pathway that offers the highest risk on the network, and performed Monte Carlo (MC) simulation, and analyzed the result.

#### **EDUCATION**:

Tennessee Tech University	Cookeville, TN
Ph.D. (Computer Science)	2018 – Present
Tennessee State University	Nashville, TN
M.S. (Computer and Information System Engineering)	2016 - 2018
Tribhuvan University	Kathmandu, Nepal
B.E. (Electronics & Computer Engineering)	2011 - 2015

#### **EXPERIENCES:**

**Tennessee Tech University**Graduate Teaching and Research Assistant

Cookeville, TN 2018 – Present

- Currently working on research related to anomaly/fraud detection in streaming (dynamic) networks such as Denial-of-Service attacks (DoS) in computer networks, social networks impersonations, or fake recommendations in e-commerce networks, etc. using graph-based techniques like probabilistic, embedding, and sketching.
- <u>Assisted Courses</u>: Discrete Structures for CSC, Foundation of CSC, Database Management Systems, Data Structures and Algorithms

# Tennessee Tech University Internship (Research Assistant)

Cookeville, TN May 2018 – Aug 2018

• Formally analyzed the transmission scheduling process of the WirelessHART networks using Satisfiability Modulo Theories (SMT). That is, this research formally models the WirelessHART networks configuration and various constraints (like number of channels, and flow deadline) as inputs and verifies the schedulability of the packets under certain success specifications.

# **Tennessee State University**Graduate Research Assistant

*Nashville, TN* 2016 – 2018

• Performed research on network security; finding a stepping stone path towards the node which has the highest impact on the network (i.e., the node whose exploitation causes the greatest loss on the organization). So that defenders can mitigate network attack problems by either changing any of the paths towards node or sifting node to the place where it will be more secure.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Language: Python, C, C++, MATLAB/Octave, SQL, LaTeX.

Software Tools: Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Scipy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly,

Tableau, Weka, Git/Github, Jupyter Notebook, NPView, Nmap, OPNET, Wireshark, NS2,

Network Simulator.

Data Skill: Anomaly/Fraud Detection, Machine Learning, Data Mining, Data Visualization, Data

Cleaning, Graph Mining, Time-series Analysis.

**Database:** MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server.

#### **PUBLICATIONS:**

2018 P. B. Lamichhane, L. Hong and S. Shetty, "A Quantitative Risk Analysis Model and Simulation of

Enterprise Networks," 2018 IEEE 9th Annual Information Technology, Electronics and Mobile

Communication Conference (IEMCON), 2018, pp. 844-850, <u>10.1109/IEMCON.2018.8615080</u>
Under P. B. Lamichhane, W. Eberle, "Anomaly Detection in Edge Streams Using Term Frequence of the Communication Conference (IEMCON), 2018, pp. 844-850, <u>10.1109/IEMCON.2018.8615080</u>

Under P. B. Lamichhane, W. Eberle, "Anomaly Detection in Edge Streams Using Term Frequency-Review Inverse Graph Frequency (TF-IGF) Concept," 2021 IEEE International Conference on Big Data

(IEEE BigData 2021).

### **P**RESENTATIONS:

**Research Paper Presentation**, 2018 IEEE 9th Annual Information Technology, Electronics and Mobile Communication Conference (IEMCON), University of British Columbia, Canada.

**Research Presentation,** on "Anomaly Detection in Edge Streams Using Term Frequency-Inverse Graph Frequency (TF-IGF) Concept", at the Graduate Student Seminar, 2021.

## **RESEARCH INTERESTS:**

- Graph-based Anomaly Detection
- Graph Embedding and Sketching
- Cyber Security Data Analysis
- Anomaly/ Fraud Detection
- Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence
- Network Security

### **CERTIFICATIONS:**

• *Machine Learning* 

• Applied Data Science with Python

Stanford University University of Michigan

800 E. Spring St., Apt H5, Cookeville, TN-38501

(615) 495-3043

<u>pblamichha42@tntech.edu</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/prabin-lamichhane-660a44147/</u>